# **Dean Petty**

🕈 Wisconsin, United States 🗷 dean.petty@gmail.com 🛘 8152986006 🛅 linkedin.com/in/dean-petty-386a237b 🕳 github.com/criticalfault

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the marketing and advertising industry. Skilled in PHP, JavaScript and Web Development. Engineering professional with a Bachelor's Degree focused in Web Design and Development program from Full Sail University.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web Developer

# Brooks-Jeffrey Marketing, Inc.

June 2017 - Present, Remote

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$  Engineer new custom development for clients.
- · Architect and engineer De Novo CMS.
- · Lead incident response on internal technology stack failures.
- · Created a monitoring tool to reduce MTTR from 5 hours to minutes.
- · Engineer custom and complex SQL and MongoDB queries for client-specific requests.
- · Lead team of front-end developers to release new features to improve user experience.
- · Migrated all existing git repositories from a file based server to Gitlab to improve accessibility for new developers and improve security.
- · Deployed Cloud Functions to GCP integrated with Pub/Sub, Cloud SQL, and Cloud Logging.

#### **Adjunct Professor**

# Arkansas State University - Mountain Home

August 2018 - July 2019, Mountain Home, AR

- · Lead Node.js Hacktoberfest project in 2018 and 2019.
- · Taught credit courses on Database and Front-End Frameworks.
- · Tutored for multiple technology disciplines.

#### **Communications Electrician**

IBEW local 364

August 2008 - June 2015, Rockford, Illinois Area

- · Hands on technical work with routing and cabling.
- · Created low-voltage wiring systems for various building types.

### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelors of Science, Web Design and Development

Fullsail University · 2017

# Journeyman Electrician, Electrician

IBEW Apprenticeship · 2011

#### **High School Graduate, General Studies**

Winnebago High School · 2003

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

## **Executive Leadership**

Lynda.com · 2017

# OSHA 30

US DEPARTMENT OF LABOR OSHA  $\cdot$  2013

#### INVOLVEMENT

#### Organizer

Second Harvest Food Bank of Central Florida · January 2017 - June 2017

## **SKILLS**

Industry Knowledge: Web Design, Programming, Agile Methodologies, Project Management, Construction Safety, Inspection, Troubleshooting, Contractors, Networking, PHP Frameworks

Tools & Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, PHP, C#, Node.js, Python, Relational Databases, MongoDB, Microsoft Office, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS),

Languages: English